evo.com 2019-12-15

# What is your privacy policy?

## What is your privacy policy?

### Effective Date: September 12, 2014

## **_Our Privacy Philosophy_**

Evolucion Innovations, Inc. (“evo”, “we”, “us”, “our”) is committed to protecting the privacy of our customers and site visitors. This Privacy Policy explains how we collect information about you, how we use it, and how you can request that this information be updated or corrected or its use modified. We reserve the right to amend or otherwise modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please re-visit this page periodically to check for updates.  Revisions to this Privacy Policy will be effective when posted on this Site. The date of last revision is shown at the top of the front page of this document. In addition, we may supplement our current Privacy Policy with additional notices of our information practices specific to certain programs or activities. 

## Contents

  * Collection of Information
  * Use of Information
  * Sharing of Information
  * Social Sharing Features
  * Security
  * Internet Technologies Used
  * Children's Privacy
  * Links from our Services to Other Websites
  * Your Choices
  * Third Party Advertising, Analytics and Services
  * Your California Privacy Rights
  * Your EU Privacy Rights
  * Changes to this Policy
  * Contact Us

## Collection of Information

We collect information you provide us on servers located in the United States. We collect information when, for example, you create an online account with us, use our website and mobile features (together, “Services”), purchase or rent from us, enter the contests, promotions, events and newsletters we sponsor or otherwise provide us information about yourself. The type of information we collect may include: 

  * Account information we may collect includes your name, postal and e-mail address, phone number, social media username(s), and any information you may share about your interests and preferences.
  * Transaction information we may collect includes account information as well as your credit card information and transaction history.
  * Information we may collect related to evo demos, events and sponsored trips includes, if and as applicable, health & fitness specifics, activity proficiency, dietary requirements and emergency contact information among other things.

We may also automatically collect information about you when you access or use our Services. Automatically collected data may include log-in information (browser type, access date & time, publisher IP, etc.), device information (hardware type/model, operating system and, if using evo’s in-store wifi network, browsing history) as well as your location information if required.  

In addition, we may use cookies, web beacons, and other tracking technologies to collect information about you and your interaction with our Services, including information about your browsing and purchase behavior on our website and other interaction with our Services. We use this information in one or more of the ways described in the "Use of Information" section below. Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default, but typically you can change your browser settings to remove or reject cookies. 

## Use of Information

The information we collect is generally used to process your requests or transactions, provide you with the Services, personalize them to you and maintain and improve their quality, tell you about opportunities we think will be of interest, monitor and analyze your use and behavior patterns, and understand your needs so that we can serve you better. For example, we may use your telephone number, your e-mail or your postal address to communicate about opportunities and programs. If you prefer not to receive Promotional Information from us, we make it easy for you to let us know. You can contact us at any time to request an update to your personal information on file or modify our use of it (see Your Choices below).

We store and process information on computer servers located in the United States.  

## Sharing of Information

We may share personal information about you outside of the evo family. For example: 

  * We may provide to a third party certain information that is necessary to fulfill an order you have placed with us. For example, if you request shipment for a purchase, we may provide your address to the shipping carrier, and if you pay by a credit or debit card, your card number and sales transaction information are passed on to the card processor and/or issuer (including their service providers such as fraud verification services). However, we give vendors, suppliers, and others involved in the commercial distribution chain only the information needed to provide you the products or services you order, such as shipping and/or billing address, e-mail address, telephone number and product orders. Moreover, we require them to keep the information confidential and not to use it for other purposes. We are not responsible for any additional information you provide directly to these parties, and we encourage you to become familiar with their practices before disclosing information directly to them.
  * When you participate in the interactive areas of our Services, such as chat rooms, forums, message boards or news groups (if any), certain information about you may be displayed publicly on our Services and on third party sites, such as your photos, posts, and other information you choose to provide in your profile or during that session. We do not routinely monitor or retain logs or copies of these interactive areas, if any, that may be available on our Services. However, you should be aware that your use and disclosure of any information in these areas is governed by our [Terms of Use](https://www.evo.com/terms-and-conditions-of-service).
  * We may also provide access to data that include your information in connection with the contemplated or actual financing, securitization, insuring, merger, sale or other encumbrance, divestiture or disposal of all or part of our business or assets, including for the purposes of determining whether to proceed with the transaction or fulfilling any records or other reporting requirements to relevant third parties. In the event of any actual transaction involving transfer of ownership or encumbrance, your personal information, among other things, may be transferred as part of the transaction.
  * We also may share your information when you specifically ask or authorize us to do so, or when we conclude disclosure is reasonably necessary to comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request, to enforce our agreements and policies, and where circumstances otherwise warrant doing so. 

## Social Sharing Features

The Services may offer social sharing features or other integrated tools, which let you share actions you take on the Services with other media, and vice versa.  The use of such features enables the sharing of information with your friends or the public, depending on the settings you establish with the third party providers of the social sharing features you select.  Your use of any social sharing features offered by the Services is governed by our [Terms of Use](https://www.evo.com/terms-and-conditions-of-service) and this Privacy Policy. For more information about the purpose and scope of data collection and processing in connection with third-party social sharing platforms, please visit the third-party providers’ privacy policies. 

## Security

We take commercially reasonable measures to secure and store your personal information to protect against its loss, misuse or alteration while under our control. We use industry standard security measures when accepting your credit card information during the online ordering process, as well as whenever we ask you to login to any of our Services. That said, data transmission over the Internet is not 100% secure. Although we use industry standard security measures, we do not guarantee against the loss, misuse or alteration of any information during its delivery or under our control. We thus urge you to always take care how you handle and disclose your personal information over the Internet   

## Internet Technologies Used

Cookies, web beacons and other relevant Internet technologies are used on our Services to allow us to accomplish the uses set out in this Privacy Policy as well as to deliver Service messaging and to keep track of your information. These small pieces of program code or “files” reside on your computer hard drive and browser and can be removed. If you desire to remove the technologies you may do so, but this may render our Services unusable to you. You can opt out of cookies or the other Internet technologies used by disabling these features in your browser program. Consult your browser’s “Help” menu for assistance in changing cookie settings or removing cookie files. 

## Children's Privacy

We are very sensitive to the issue of children’s privacy. Our Services are neither developed for, nor directed at, children under 13 years old. If you believe your child has provided us with personal information, or registered with one of our Services and would like to have this information removed, please contact our privacy representative at [privacy@evo.com](mailto:privacy@evo.com) for assistance. 

## Links from Our Services to Other Websites

Our Services may contain links to third-party owned or operated websites. When you access these external websites, the providers of the websites, which may include product or service vendors and other unrelated parties, may have access to certain information about you. Please be aware that once you have left our Services, we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any websites that we do not control directly and the collection, use and disclosure of information about you by these entities will be subject to the privacy policies applicable at those other websites. 

## Your Choices

**Your Information.  **You may update or correct information about you by logging into your online account or emailing privacy@evo.com. You may also email us at this same address if you wish to deactivate your account, but note that we may retain certain information about you for archival, safety notice and other legal or business purposes.

**Promotional Communications.  **You may opt out of receiving promotional emails and text messages from evo by following the instructions in those communications or by contacting evo customer care [here](https://www.evo.com/customer-care-phone-hours). If you opt out of receiving promotional communications, we may still send you non-promotional emails that, for example, relate to your purchases, your account or our ongoing business relations. 

**Location Information.**  You also have the ability to turn location-based services on and off by adjusting the settings of your Internet browser or mobile device, or by following the standard uninstall process and removing all evo applications, if any,from your mobile device. 

Notwithstanding the foregoing or any other provision in this Privacy Policy, you may not be permitted to withdraw your permission or consent to certain necessary uses and disclosures of your personal information, for example, but not limited to, providing product safety and recall announcements and services, maintaining reasonable business and transaction records, and disclosures required by applicable laws. In addition, we may be required or permitted under various federal, state and/or foreign laws to collect, use or disclose your information without your consent, for example, to comply with a valid subpoena, court order or governmental inquiry, or to collect a debt owed to us. We expressly reserve all rights described in this paragraph. 

## Third Party Advertising, Analytics and Services

We allow third parties to serve advertisements on our behalf across the Internet and to provide analytics services. These third parties may use similar technologies to collect the same or similar information as we use and collect to analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, deliver advertising and content that aligns with your interests on our Services and other websites, and to better understand, generally, your online activity. This Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we are not responsible for, third party technologies and we encourage you to check the privacy policies of these third parties to learn more about their privacy practices.

We also use a third party to "power" product reviews on our Services. When you submit a product review, you become subject to the terms of use and privacy policy of this third party, and the reviews you submit may be posted on our Services and on third party websites.

## Your California Privacy Rights

California law permits residents of California to request certain details about how their information is shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes. However, under the law, a business is not required to provide this information if it permits California residents to optin to, or opt out of  this type of sharing. evo qualifies for this alternative option. To opt out of having your information shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes, please [call Customer Service](https://www.evo.com/customer-care-phone-hours). 

## Visitors from outside the U.S.

We are based in the U.S. and the information we collect is governed by U.S. law. If you are visiting the Site from outside the U.S., please be aware that information we obtain through the Site or our Services may be transferred to, processed, stored and used in the U.S. Data protection laws in the U.S. may be different from those of your country of residence. Your use of the Site or our Services constitutes your consent to the transfer to and from, processing, usage, sharing and storage of your information, including Personal Information, in the U.S. as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

evo may change this Privacy Policy from time to time in at sole discretion. Each time changes are made, we revise the Effective Date above. We encourage you to periodically review the Privacy Policy to insure you have the most current version and to stay informed about our information practices and the ways you can help protect your privacy. 

## Contact Us

If you want to update or access your personal information, or if you have any questions, comments or concerns about this Privacy Policy or our privacy practices, please contact our privacy officer at [privacy@evo.com](mailto:privacy@evo.com). You may also direct your privacy-related requests, comments or questions to the following address:

evo  
Attention: Privacy Officer  
122 NW 36th St  
Seattle, WA 98107
